Guide to the Boatman Family Papers, 1901-1981 and undated RL.00125
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Boatman Family papers
1901-1981 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Boatman family
RL.00125
72 Linear Feet
Methodist educators and family members from Kentucky and Alabama. The Boatman Family Papers span the years 1901-1981; the majority of the papers were generated by the Rev. Dr. Conway and Mrs. Caroline Boatman, Methodist educators from Kentucky. The collection is arranged in series by family member and institution, the most substantial series being the Conway and Caroline Boatman Series; the John Paul Boatman Series; and the Union College Series. Other smaller groups pertain to other family members. Family correspondence makes up the majority of the collection, but there are also scrapbooks; educational records (primarily financial); many photographs of Union College in Barbourville, Kentucky; and clippings and other printed items. Topics covered by the correspondence in the Conway and Caroline's papers cover their courtship (1909-1919); the Methodist Episcopal mission in Jubbulpore, India (1919-1923); and India Methodist Theological College (1923-1925). There are also many references to the three institutions where Dr. Boatman served as President - Iowa National Bible Training School (1928-1931), Snead College in Boaz, Ala., and College of Barbourville, Ky. (1939-1959). Fund-raising, especially during the Depression, is a commonly recurring theme. Other letters from sons of the Boatmans refer to their college years from the 1930s-1940s. Institutions referred to here include Drew University, University of Kentucky in Lexington, and Southwestern College in Kansas.
8620 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Boatman Family Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase from 1983-1981.
Collection Overview
The Boatman Family Papers span the years 1901-1981; the majority of the papers were generated by the Rev. Dr. Conway and Mrs. Caroline Boatman, Methodist educators from Kentucky. The collection is arranged in series by family member and institution, the most substantial series being the Conway and Caroline Boatman Series; the John Paul Boatman Series; and the Union College Series. Other smaller groups pertain to other family members. Family correspondence makes up the majority of the collection, but there are also scrapbooks; educational records (primarily financial); many photographs of Union College in Barbourville, Kentucky; and clippings and other printed items. Topics covered by the correspondence in the Conway and Caroline's papers cover their courtship (1909-1919); the Methodist Episcopal mission in Jubbulpore, India (1919-1923); and India Methodist Theological College (1923-1925). There are also many references to the three institutions where Dr. Boatman served as President - Iowa National Bible Training School (1928-1931), Snead College in Boaz, Ala., and College of Barbourville, Ky. (1939-1959). Fund-raising, especially during the Depression, is a commonly recurring theme. Other letters from sons of the Boatmans refer to their college years from the 1930s-1940s. Institutions referred to here include Drew University, University of Kentucky in Lexington, and Southwestern College in Kansas.
Education, Higher -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States; Courtship; College students -- United States; College teachers -- Correspondence; Missionaries -- India; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Boatman, Conway; Boatman, John Paul; Boatman family; Boatman, Caroline; Iowa National Bible Training School; Methodist Church -- Missions -- India; Drew University; India Methodist Mission; Union College (Ky.); University of Kentucky; Snead College (Ala.); Southwestern College (Winfield, Kansas) -- Campus life
- Conway and Caroline Boatman Series, 1909-1981 and undated, 36 boxes
  - Correspondence, 1909-1919 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1919 (Box 49)
  - Correspondence, 1920-1927 Mar. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1927 Apr.-1928 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1928 (Box 49)
  - Correspondence, 1929- 1931 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1932-1933 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1934-1935 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1938-1939 Apr. (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1939 May- Dec. (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, 1930-1938 (Box 49)
  - Correspondence,1940 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence,1941 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence,1942 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 49)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1944 Aug. (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1944 Sept.-1945 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1952 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, 1952-1958 (Box 49)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1968 (Box 49)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1968 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1978 (Box 49)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1981 and undated (Box 26)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 49)
  - Correspondence, John Lakin Brasher, 1924-1975 and undated (Box 26)
  - Legal and Financial Papers (Box 27)
  - Writings, Miscellaneous Authors (Box 27)
  - Notes, general (Box 28)
  - Notes, general, undated (Box 49)
  - Notes, India Methodist Theological College (Box 29)
  - Miscellany (Box 29)
  - Miscellany and clippings (Box 49)
  - Clippings (Box 30)
    - General (Box 30)
    - John Lakin Brasher (Box 30)
    - Snead College (Box 30)
  - Printed Material (Box 30)
  - India (Box 31)
    - India: Methodist Church (Box 31)
    - India: Snead College (Box 31)
  - Pictures (Box 32)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 32)
    - Family (Box 32)
    - John. L. Brasher (Box 32)
    - Snead College (Box 32)
  - Scrapbooks and other volumes (Box 33-36)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 49)
- John Paul Boatman Series, 1934-1937, 1 box
  - Correspondence, 1934-1937 (Box 37)
- Joseph Brasher Boatman Series, 1938-1948 and undated, 2 boxes
  - Correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box 37)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1948 and undated (Box 38)
- Michael Wilson Boatman Series, 1946-1981 and undated, 2 boxes
  Conditions Governing Access note
  [CLOSED to research until Jan. 1 2010.]
  - Correspondence, 1946-1962 (Box 38)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1981 and undated (Box 39)
- Eula Brasher Series, 1936-1976 and undated, 1 box
  - Correspondence, 1936-1976 and undated (Box 40)
- Union College Series, 1936-1972 and undated, 8 boxes
  - Correspondence, 1957-1961 (Box 41)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1965 (Box 42)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1972 and undated (Box 43)
  - Financial Papers (Box 44)
    - General (Box 44)
    - Finance Promotion Report (Box 44)
    - Phase II Development Drive (Box 44)
    - Solicitations (Box 44)
  - Writings (Box 45)
    - General (Box 45)
    - Report of the President to the Board of Trustees, 1936-1959 (Box 45)
    - Trustee Newsletter, 1963-1973 (Box 45)
  - Miscellany (Box 46)
  - Clippings (Box 46)
  - Pictures (Box 47-48)
- Oversize Material
  - Miscellaneous Oversize (Oversize-folder Folder 1)